<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>privacy - Tag - ~# SpyF0x_</title><link>https://spyfox.me/tags/privacy/</link><description>privacy - Tag - ~# SpyF0x_</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://spyfox.me/tags/privacy/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to know if you are being spied on by your FBI agent</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/privacy/how-to-know-if-you-are-being-spied-on/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/privacy/how-to-know-if-you-are-being-spied-on/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/tutorials/canary/canary-token.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Is someone reading your messages ? How can you be sure that no one is viewing the documents you store on your computer ?
These are some questions that may be lingering in your head and may lead you to think that someone is spying on you, lurking in the shadows, waiting like a lioness to pounce on her prey
But how to be sure ? Here come Canary Tokens</description></item><item><title>Pi-hole or how to adblock your whole network</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/system/linux/raspberry/pi-hole-or-how-to-adblock-your-whole-network/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/system/linux/raspberry/pi-hole-or-how-to-adblock-your-whole-network/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/tutorials/pihole.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Pi-hole is a powerful network-level ad blocker that acts as a local DNS and possibly as a DHCP server. You can easily block ads on all your devices (TV, computers, phones, etc.)
A bit of background The Pi-hole project was created by Jacob Salmela as an open source alternative to AdTrap in 2014 and was hosted on GitHub. Since then, several contributors have joined the project, including dschaper, PromoFaux and DL6ER.</description></item><item><title>Replace Google Analytics with a script</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/system/browser/replace-google-analytics-with-a-script/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/system/browser/replace-google-analytics-with-a-script/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/tutorials/umami/replace-google-anal-with-umami0.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Here is a guide to swap the Google Analytics with Umami, a free, open source and privacy friendly app to selfhost.
A bit of background  Google Analytics is one of most evil tools you must to get rid off for the sake of your visitors. Don&rsquo;t be fooled by all the functionnalities it offers : do you really need to know the age and the gender of your visitors ?]]></description></item><item><title>Replace the google (or any privacy killer) newsfeed</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/system/android/replace-the-google-newsfeed/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/system/android/replace-the-google-newsfeed/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/tutorials/google-news/replace-the-google-%28or-any-privacy-killer%29-newsfeed0.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Here is a guide to swap the Google newsfeed with RSS feeds, a free, open source and privacy friendly alternative.
A bit of background&hellip;  RSS feeds are a way to simply get news from the websites you choose to follow. They include article titles, summaries and links to view them directly into your browser.
With RSS feeds, there is no need for a newsletter, it&rsquo;s your rss reader which automatically connects to the feed to see if there is new content and display it to you.]]></description></item></channel></rss>