<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Defensive Security - Category - ~# SpyF0x_</title><link>https://spyfox.me/categories/defensive-security/</link><description>Defensive Security - Category - ~# SpyF0x_</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://spyfox.me/categories/defensive-security/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DMZ : One click to get hacked</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/network/dmz-one-click-to-get-hacked/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/network/dmz-one-click-to-get-hacked/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/security/dmz/dmz-background.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>By design, your gateway has a set of firewall rules to prevent anyone from reaching directly your devices from the Internet
But this same gateway, has also an option called DMZ to cancel this protection.
First things first Originally, it is a set of rules to ensure that a server will be connected to the Internet, but will not be able to access the local network :
Your server becomes the front door of your network.</description></item><item><title>Endlessh : Troll any hacker with this cool SSH blackhole !</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/network/endlessh-troll-any-hacker-with-this-cool-ssh-blackhole-/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/network/endlessh-troll-any-hacker-with-this-cool-ssh-blackhole-/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/security/spyfox-endlessh.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Firewalls, brute force detection, SSH on random port, geoip filtering, honeypots&hellip;
There are LOTS of ideas to make life hard for the bot army that constantly probes the internet.
Well, thanks to &ldquo;skeeto&rdquo; you can add &ldquo;Endlessh&rdquo; to this list !
How does it work ?  According to the official Github repository, Endlessh is an SSH tarpit that very slowly sends an endless, random SSH banner.
It keeps SSH clients locked up for hours or even days at a time.]]></description></item><item><title>Secure your GNU/Linux server with these few iptables rules</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/system/secure-your-gnu-linux-server-with-these-few-iptables-rules/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/system/secure-your-gnu-linux-server-with-these-few-iptables-rules/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/tutorials/iptables-secure-your-linux-server0.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>The simple fact that your server is accessible on the Internet means that it is being attacked every 39 seconds on average.
That is more than 2,215 times in a day !
Should we simply stop having servers ? Of course not !
Why such attacks ? When I say this kind of things (which are actually true) many people take it as a joke or worse, are skeptical :</description></item><item><title>How to block Log4j with fail2ban</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/system/how-to-block-log4j-with-fail2ban/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/system/how-to-block-log4j-with-fail2ban/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/security/log4j-fail2ban.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>So today, we will see how to detect and immediately ban using fail2ban, all the creeps that try to exploit your servers with log4j.
First things first  If you haven&rsquo;t done so yet, check out here the official CISA log4j vulnerability guidance, which includes all the responses from a bunch of software vendors.
The problem The problem with the internet is that too many computers, in my opinion, have for the sole purpose to scan and detect all accessible and vulnerable servers.]]></description></item><item><title>PPA &amp; AUR : A security hole in Ubuntu &amp; Arch Linux ?</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/system/ppa-aur-a-security-hole-in-ubuntu-arch-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/system/ppa-aur-a-security-hole-in-ubuntu-arch-linux/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/security/security-aur-ppa/security-aur-ppa0.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Arch Linux and Ubuntu are both excellent distributions whose security is taken very seriously by their people, but these two behemoths both have a BIG Achilles heel.
First things first  Don&rsquo;t get me wrong folks, I really like the philosophy behind those two distributions :
 Making Linux accessible to anyone for Ubuntu Pushing customization to the limit for Arch Linux (as long as we have nothing against systemd)  I also spent a lot of time on these two distributions using them as daily drivers, and they are both great !]]></description></item><item><title>DIY - Turn an old PC into a powerful Firewall using OPNsense</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/network/diy-turn-an-old-pc-into-a-powerful-router-firewall-ids-using-opnsense/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/network/diy-turn-an-old-pc-into-a-powerful-router-firewall-ids-using-opnsense/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/tutorials/opnsense/diy-opnsense.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Today, I will show you how to build a powerful open source (FOSS) router secured with a dedicated firewall and its own IDS (Suricata) at no cost.
Go get your old laptop or PC get follow this DIY !
First things first  When I talk to someone about cybersecurity, I often hear the price argument coming up. &ldquo;Yeah, if you want a real level of security, you need dedicated equipment, and it costs a lot of money, etc.]]></description></item><item><title>WiFi - How to secure at best your WiFi from hackers</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/network/wifi-how-to-secure-at-best-your-wifi-from-hackers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/network/wifi-how-to-secure-at-best-your-wifi-from-hackers/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/tutorials/wifi/wifi-protect/wifi-protect.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>As you could see on this tutorial WiFi is vulnerable to a plethora of attack. Don&rsquo;t let any creepy stranger get into your home/company network with this tutorial !
First things first  When you go on the Internet, everything you see or download is actually contained in thousands of little messages (a bit like postal mail) that are then put back in order by your computer. These messages (like mail) have a header (recipient, sender, date, etc.]]></description></item><item><title>Facebook - What can we learn from Facebook's business disruption</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/web/facebook-what-can-we-can-learn-from-facebooks-business-disruption/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/web/facebook-what-can-we-can-learn-from-facebooks-business-disruption/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/security/facebook-down/facebook-down.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Every downtime is an opportunity to learn, even for companies like Facebook Inc. that seem unwilling to learn from mistakes in other areas.
A little bit of context  Facebook Inc. experienced a severe outage in its main operations on Monday, Oct. 4. The massive downtime was difficult for those responsible for building and maintaining its technology and applications to cope with. While downtime is not new to Facebook, this outage is certainly one that will go down in the company&rsquo;s history books.]]></description></item><item><title>Don't be fooled by this kind of UNIX-like backdoors</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/system/dont-be-fooled-by-this-new-kind-of-unix-like-backdoors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/protection/system/dont-be-fooled-by-this-new-kind-of-unix-like-backdoors/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/security/unix-backdoors/don%27t-be-fooled-by-this-kind-of-unix-backdoors.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>I am seeing more and more attacks in the wild implying the use of a setuid mechanism to maintain a privileged access onto a UNIX-like system (Linux, BSD&rsquo;s, OSX, etc.).
A little bit of context  Let&rsquo;s imagine your system being hacked by any kind, it could be either :
 An unfortunate weak password guess A malicious physical access A chad NSA 0day slamming your ports &hellip;    As you are someone who knows a little bit about IT security, you successfully manage to patch your system and change all your passwords, locking out the hackers.]]></description></item></channel></rss>