<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Offensive Security - Category - ~# SpyF0x_</title><link>https://spyfox.me/categories/offensive-security/</link><description>Offensive Security - Category - ~# SpyF0x_</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://spyfox.me/categories/offensive-security/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to reset a forgotten password (Raspberry Pi edition)</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/offensive/system/how-to-reset-a-forgotten-password-raspberry-pi-edition/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/offensive/system/how-to-reset-a-forgotten-password-raspberry-pi-edition/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/security/raspberry-passw/raspberry-passw0.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>So today, we&rsquo;re going to look at how to hack your own Raspberry Pi in order to break any system authentication.
A bit of background  Last week, I wanted to make sure that my favorite device, a proud Raspberry Pi, was secure because there was an important vulnerability on a software I knew was installed on it.
Happy to open a terminal in order to connect via SSH to this little wonder, my pleasure was interrupted when I saw this :]]></description></item><item><title>How to crack any WiFi (WEP-WPA-WPA2-WPA3-WPS)</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/offensive/network/wifi-crack-your-neighbors-wifi-wep-wpa-wpa2-copy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/offensive/network/wifi-crack-your-neighbors-wifi-wep-wpa-wpa2-copy/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/tutorials/wifi/wifi-crack/wifi-crack.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>I&rsquo;m assuming that you are successfully operating a proper GNU/Linux distribution (if not, go check this tutorial) and that you&rsquo;re not lame enough to imagine connecting to a WiFi network without a WiFi card or a USB WiFi adapter.
First things first  When you go on the Internet, everything you see or download is actually contained in thousands of little messages (a bit like postal mail) that are then put back in order by your computer.]]></description></item><item><title>Hacking - How to practice legally</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/offensive/red-team/capture-the-flag/hacking-how-to-practice-legally/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/offensive/red-team/capture-the-flag/hacking-how-to-practice-legally/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/security/vulnhub/vulnhub.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>If you want to practice Ethical Hacking, there are lots of websites like HackTheBox wich provide you challenges in several cybersecurity fields (e.g. networking, cryptanalysis, etc.)
But those platforms are most of the time companies wich have to be always online and hence, have strong security policies.
For instance, they can&rsquo;t allow you to bruteforce their challenges or to DDOS their entire infrastructure.   They have a limited number of environments and so sometimes it&rsquo;s just not possible to have fun since everything is laggy because of people doing some bruteforcing or anything else that challenges their infrastructures.]]></description></item><item><title>Web pentesting - Fundamentals</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/offensive/web/web-pentesting-fundamentals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/offensive/web/web-pentesting-fundamentals/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/security/web-pentest/web-pentest.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The objective of a web pentest is to evaluate the security of web application by simulating a cyberattack.
A little bit of context  The auditor&rsquo;s job can be separated into two main activities: identifying vulnerabilities (Vulnerability Assessment) and using them to perform a full penetration test (Pentest).
Companies may request the services of an auditor only to run a Nessus (or OpenVAS) scan on an IP address range, without authorizing an actual intrusion.]]></description></item><item><title>The black magic behind denial of service attacks</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/offensive/network/the-black-magic-behind-denial-of-service-attacks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/offensive/network/the-black-magic-behind-denial-of-service-attacks/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/security/denial-of-service/black%20magic%20behind%20denial%20of%20service%20attacks.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>A denial of service attack is when an application (or anything else) is prevented from doing what it was designed to do.
A little bit of context  Denial of service (or DoS) attacks are back in the news every year. Whether it&rsquo;s with the breakdown of Xbox live, Playstation Network or Steam servers, the goal is always the same:
to prevent an application or a server from doing its job.]]></description></item><item><title>XSS - Fundamentals</title><link>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/offensive/web/xss-fundamentals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://spyfox.me/posts/cybersecurity/offensive/web/xss-fundamentals/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/security/xss-fundamentals/xss-fundamentals.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>You have certainly already heard about XSS. But what is really a Cross Site Scripting (XSS), how can a hacker exploit this kind of vulnerability and for what purpose ?
A little bit of context We regularly hear about Cross Site Scripting. Depending on your level, you know that it is either has something to do with JavaScript or, if you are keen on computer security, you could even state that XSS is a security flaw allowing a user of the site to inject JavaScript code into a web page.</description></item></channel></rss>